<?xml version="1.0"?>
<!DOCTYPE article PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.1.2//EN" 
"http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.1.2/docbookx.dtd" [
]>
<!-- =============Document Header ============================= -->

<article id="index" lang="en"> 
  <articleinfo>
    <title>Reporting GNOME Bugs and Other Feedback</title>

    <abstract role="description">
      <para>This document describes how to report a bug you have found with an
      GNOME application, and how to go about giving feedback about the GNOME Desktop.</para>
    </abstract>

    <copyright>
      <year>2001</year>
      <year>2003</year>
      <holder>GNOME Documentation Project</holder>
    </copyright>    
    <publisher> 
      <publishername> GNOME Documentation Project </publishername> 
    </publisher> 
    <authorgroup>
    <author>
		<firstname>Alexander</firstname> 
		<surname>Kirillov</surname> 
     </author> 
    </authorgroup>
    <legalnotice id="legalnotice">
      <para>
  	  Permission is granted to copy, distribute and/or modify this
	  document under the terms of the GNU Free Documentation
	  License (GFDL), Version 1.1 or any later version published
	  by the Free Software Foundation with no Invariant Sections,
	  no Front-Cover Texts, and no Back-Cover Texts.  You can find
	  a copy of the GFDL at this <ulink type="help"
	  url="ghelp:fdl">link</ulink> or in the file COPYING-DOCS
	  distributed with this document.
     </para>
      <para>
        Many of the names used by companies to distinguish their
        products and services are claimed as trademarks. Where those
        names appear in any GNOME documentation, and those trademarks
        are made aware to the members of the GNOME Documentation
        Project, the names have been printed in caps or initial caps.
      </para>
    </legalnotice>


    <releaseinfo>
       This is version 2.0 of gnome-feedback document
    </releaseinfo>

  </articleinfo>



<!-- ============= DOCUMENT BODY ================================ -->

 <sect1 id="feedback-main">
  <title>Feedback information</title>
    <sect2 id="bugreports">
    <title>Reporting Bugs</title>  

      <para>
     If you have found a bug in one of GNOME applications, please
   report it! Developers do read all the bug reports and try to fix
   these bugs. Please try to be as specific as possible when
   describing the circumstances under which the bug shows (what
   commands did you enter? which buttons did you click?). If there were any
   error messages, be sure to include them, too.  
      </para> 
      <para>
	The easiest way to report bugs is by using <application>Bug
	  Report Tool</application> (<command>bug-buddy</command>),
	  available in the <guisubmenu>Programming</guisubmenu> submenu
	  of <guimenu>Applications</guimenu> menu. This utility will guide you
	  through the bug reporting process; it will also
	  automatically collect some information necessary for
	  developers, such as versions of the operating system and
	  libraries you are using.
      </para>
      <para>
	You can also submit bugs and browse the list of known bugs by
	connecting to the <ulink type="http"
	url="http://bugzilla.gnome.org/">GNOME bug tracking
	database</ulink>.  You will need to register before you can
	submit any bugs this way — and do not forget to read
	<ulink type="http"
	url="http://bugzilla.gnome.org/bugwritinghelp.html">Bug
	Writing Guidelines</ulink>. 
      </para>
      
      <para>
	Please note that some of GNOME applications are developed by
	commercial companies (these products are still free
	software). For example, <application>Evolution</application>
	groupware suite is developed by <ulink type="http"
	url="http://www.ximian.com">Ximian</ulink>. Bugs reports and
	comments about these products should be directed to the
	respective companies. If you are using <application>Bug Report
	Tool</application>, it will automatically send bug reports to
	the correct database.
	</para>


    </sect2>
    <sect2 id="wishlist"> 
      <title>Suggestions and Comments</title> 
      <para> 
	If you have a suggestion or want to request a new feature for
      one of the applications, it can also be done using the bug
      tracking database. Submit your suggestion as a bug report as
      described in <xref linkend="bugreports" /> and at the appropriate
      step select <guilabel>Severity: Enhancement</guilabel>. 
      </para>
    </sect2>

      <sect2 id="docs">
      <title>Documentation Comments</title>

      <para> If you found an inaccuracy or misprint in one of GNOME
	documents, or have any comments or suggestions about
	documentation, please let us know! The easiest way of doing so
	is by submitting a bug report as explained before and
	selecting <guilabel>Component: docs</guilabel> at appropriate
	steps (or <guilabel>general</guilabel> if there is no
	<guilabel>docs</guilabel> component). If your comment is about
	general GNOME documentation (such as <citetitle>GNOME Users
	Guide</citetitle>) rather than specific application manual,
	select <guilabel>Product: gnome-user-docs</guilabel>.
      </para>
      <para>
	Alternatively, you can just send your comments by email to the
	<ulink type="http"
	url="http://live.gnome.org/DocumentationProject">GNOME
	Documentation Project</ulink> mailing list; our address is
	<email>gnome-doc-list@gnome.org</email>. And by the way: if you are not
	a developer but want to help GNOME —
	<ulink type="http"
	url="http://live.gnome.org/DocumentationProject/Join">join
	the GDP</ulink> and help us  improve GNOME documentation.
      </para>
    </sect2>

 </sect1>

</article>

